They delivered the papers, until they made the headlines...
Newsies is a music, comedy, drama film directed by Brett Sullivan.
A week in the life of the exploited, child newspaper
sellers in turn-of-the-century New York.
When their publisher, Joseph Pulitzer, tries to squeeze a little more profit out of their labours,
they organize a strike, only to be confronted with the Pulitzer's hard-ball tactics.
Jack Kelly, played by Jeremy Jordan.
Katherine, played by Kara Lindsay.
Davey, played by Ben Fankhauser.
Crutchie, played by Andrew Keenan-Bolger.
Joseph Pulitzer, played by Steve Blanchard.
Medda Larkin, played by Aisha de Haas.
Newsies is a 1992 American historical musical drama
film produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by choreographer Kenny Ortega and written by Bob Tzudiker and Noni White,
it is loosely based on the New York City newsboys' strike of 1899.
Featuring twelve original songs by Alan Menken with lyrics
by Jack Feldman and an underscore by J.
Redford, it stars Christian Bale, Bill Pullman, Ann-Margret, and Robert Duvall.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a box-office
bomb, grossing $3 million against a $15M budget.
However, it later gained a cult following on home video, and was
ultimately adapted into a stage musical on Broadway.
The play was nominated for eight Tony Awards, winning two
including Best Original Score for Menken and Feldman.
The film explores themes of new york city, musical, based on
true story, based on play or musical, love.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.